Guide to the David Hamburg papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Carnegie Corporation of New York
  - Subseries I.5: Carnegie Commission on Science, Technology and Government (CCSTG)
    Materials on Carnegie Corporation sponsorship of projects related to the issues of science and technology, including Carnegie Commission for Science, Technology and Development. (See also the corresponding series IV.B of Carnegie Corporation of New York Records). The Series includes some Science Education files, however ESTE and other Science Education programs for children are filed in Subseries I.6 (Children and Youth). Science, Technology and Development materials relating to the commonwealth countries can be found in Subseries I.3 (HRDC). National Science Foundation and AAAS, as well as Jimmy Carter played active roles in these projects, so the correspondence files (Series III.B) with these organizations can provide additional materials on the subject.
    - Subject files, 1977-1986 (Box 33, Folder 1-31)
    - Subject files, 1986-December 1987 (Box 34, Folder 1-47)
    - Subject files, 1988-May 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1-52)
    - Subject files, May 1988-October 1988 (Box 36, Folder 1-44)
    - Subject files, November 1988-March 1990 (Box 37, Folder 1-37)
    - Subject files, April 1990-November 1990 (Box 38, Folder 1-36)
    - Subject files, December 1990-June 1991 (Box 39, Folder 1-38)
    - Subject files, June 1991-March 1992 (Box 40, Folder 1-35)
    - Subject files, March 1992-September 1992 (Box 41, Folder 1-49)
    - Subject files, October 1992-2002 (Box 42, Folder 1-56)
    - CCSTG Background Materials, 1980-1987 (Box 43, Folder 1-71)
    - CCSTG Background Materials, 1987-1992 (Box 44, Folder 1-88)
  - Subseries I.6: Children and Youth
    This series included chronologically arranged correspondence, proceedings, meeting minutes, notes and background materials from a number of Children and Youth programs undertaken by the CCNY under David Hamburg’s leadership, such as Carnegie Council for Adolescent Development (CCAD), Education and Healthy Development for Children and Youth (EHDCY), Prevention of Damage to Children, Education, Science Technology and the Economy(ESTE), Task Force for Learning in Primary Grades (TFLPG) and Middle Grade School State Policy Initiative. The series also contains correspondence and reports relating to Forum on Education and the Economy, and Project 2061 under the auspices of the American Association for Advancement of Science. The files document and discuss issues of health and public policy, prenatal development, families and communities, child abuse, aggression and violence, schools and educational programs. Materials frequently contain edits of Hamburg’s earlier writings, or refer to his related previous work for other institutions. For additional materials on science education see also Subseries I.5 (CCSTG). Official records of CCAD, TFLPG and other special projects by the Carnegie Corporations can be found in the corresponding subseries of the Carnegie Corporation of New York Records, Series IV.
    - Early Subject files, 1982-January 1983 (Box 45, Folder 1-25)
    - PDC and ESTE program papers; Black Churches conference, February 1983-1984 (Box 46, Folder 1-23)
    - Multi-year files 1984-1987; 1984 TV/Media conference (Box 47, Folder 1-25)
    - TV & education; Hamburg's "Preventive Orientation" drafts, 1985-1997 (Box 48, Folder 1-22)
    - ESTE Advisory Council and Forum on Education and the Economy, January 1985-October 1985 (Box 49, Folder 1-27)
    - ESTE Advisory Council and Forum on Education and the Economy, AAAS Project 2061, November 1985-1985 (Box 50, Folder 1-18)
    - Forum on Education and the Economy, 1985-1994 (Box 51, Folder 1-32)
    - Children and Youth materials and Hamburg writings drafts, 1986- (Box 52, Folder 1-31)
    - ESTE & CCAD; minorities and the media, January 1986-July 1986 (Box 53, Folder 1-29)
    - CCAD establishment; "Way of Viewing Adolescence" papers, August 1986-November 1986 (Box 54, Folder 1-29)
    - Children and Youth materials, November 1986-1988 (Box 55, Folder 1-25)
    - Education, health and behavior linkages; Children and the Media, 1986-1989 (Box 56, Folder 1-21)
    - Children and Youth materials, 1987-1989 (Box 57, Folder 1-19)
    - CCAD first plenary meeting materials, January 1987 -February 1987 (Box 58, Folder 1-30)
    - Media Conference; Interventions for Adolescence, March 1987-May 1987 (Box 59, Folder 1-34)
    - CCAD 2nd plenary meeting; Media materials, June 1987-July 1987 (Box 60, Folder 1-26)
    - Children and Youth materials, August 1987-October 1987 (Box 61, Folder 1-33)
    - CCAD; Adolescent health & health education, November 1987-1988 (Box 62, Folder 1-21)
    - CCAD, "Turning Points" Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 63, Folder 1-21)
    - Education Advisory Council, 1988-March 1988 (Box 64, Folder 1-35)
    - Children and Youth CC retreat materials, April 1988-June 1988 (Box 65, Folder 1-32)
    - Children and Youth materials, June 1988-August 1988 (Box 66, Folder 1-25)
    - Education Advisory Council Meeting, August 1988-November 1988 (Box 67, Folder 1-23)
    - CCAD Hamburg writings and notes, December 1988-1989 (Box 68, Folder 1-17)
    - ESTE and PDC 5-year program reviews, 1989-April 1989 (Box 69, Folder 1-25)
    - Turning Points materials, April 1989-August 1989 (Box 70, Folder 1-39)
    - Children and Youth materials, September 1989-1990 (Box 71, Folder 1-27)
    - Stanford University materials; Birthstart program, 1990-May 1990 (Box 72, Folder 1-36)
    - Children and Youth materials, May 1990-November 1990 (Box 73, Folder 1-31)
    - CCAD memoranda 1990-1991, December 1990-March 1991 (Box 74, Folder 1-22)
    - Children and Youth materials, April 1991-December 1991 (Box 75, Folder 1-26)
    - CCAD memoranda and DAH writings, 1992-April 1992 (Box 76, Folder 1-22)
    - Adolescent Health Conference; Fateful Choices; Today's Children, April 1992-September 1992 (Box 77, Folder 1-38)
      See also the Jacobs Foundation and Today's Children Series
    - EHDCY program paper, DAH papers & talks, October 1992-June 1993 (Box 78, Folder 1-24)
    - CCAD meetings, memos, Final report materials, June 1993-March 1994 (Box 79, Folder 1-26)
    - Starting Points Report, Conference Materials & correspondence, January 1994-April 1994 (Box 80, Folder 1-10)
    - Starting Points, CCAD material; Hillary Clinton Memo prep, April 1994-September 1994 (Box 81, Folder 1-19)
    - CCAD report materials; presentation at IOM, 1994-1995 (Box 82, Folder 1-22)
    - TFLPG 1994-1996; CCAD Great Transitions final report materials, 1994-1995 (Box 83, Folder 1-11)
    - includes CCAD final report & meeting materials, 1995-September 1995 (Box 84, Folder 1-23)
    - Great Transitions; TFLPG: Years of Promise, October 1995-February 1996 (Box 85, Folder 1-36)
    - Hillary Clinton White house childcare conference, March 1996-1999 (Box 86, Folder 1-46)
    - Children and Youth materials, 1999-2001 (Box 87, Folder 1-23)
    - undated materials and notes (Box 87, Folder 24-47)
    - undated materials and notes (Box 88, Folder 1-27)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1982-1986 (Box 89, Folder 1-53)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 90, Folder 1-38)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 91, Folder 1-14)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 92, Folder 1-35)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1991-1993 (Box 93, Folder 1-32)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1993-1996 (Box 94, Folder 1-37)
    - Children & Youth Background Materials, 1997-2001 (Box 95, Folder 1-60)
  - Subseries I.7: Preventing Deadly Conflict (PDC)
    Preventing Deadly Conflict (PDC) series documents the cluster of CCNY programs, relating to conflict prevention, including Avoiding Nuclear War (ANW) program, Cooperative Security Program, and Carnegie Commission for Preventing Deadly Conflict (CCPDC) of 1994-1999. ANW program on national security and weapons of mass destruction reintroduced and enlarged focus on Russia though reviving Russian policy studies in key US universities, and establishing new ties with think tanks and policy makers in U.S., Eastern and Western Europe and the Soviet Union. Related material can also be found in the Correspondence (Series III) of this collection and in the Carnegie Corporation of New York Y Records Series IV.A (CCPDC). The series includes pre-CCNY materials used as the basis for CCSTG, multi-year subject files through 1989, and collection of Hamburg STG-related talks and writings 1980-1989. The series contains correspondence, event handouts, Hamburg’s writing and speeches; materials from other organizations such as NAS, Stanford, Harvard, WHO, Pugwash, etc. It includes correspondence with Mikhail Gorbachev and other Soviet officials, US congressmen, such as Senators Nunn and Lugar, documents legislation and activity on nuclear arms reduction. Most materials specifically related to projects in USSR/Russia and the Eastern Bloc countries have been separated into Subseries I.8
    - Sub-subseriesI.7.A: PDC Chronological Files
      Subject files related to Preventing Deadly Conflict issues, arranged chronologically by the date of the earliest document in a folder/box. ANW program started in 1982/3-1991; then Coop. Sec. starts 1991; PDC proper starts 1995). The files contain materials on the Gulf War of 1990, the International Court of Justice, Prevention of Proliferation (PoP) program, International Peace Academy, correspondence with Robert Rubin, Al Gore, Bill and Hilary Clinton.
      - DAH writings; ANW & PDC Program Papers, 1983-January 1984 (Box 96, Folder 1-23)
      - Harvard JFK school, IOM, AAAS, Materials, June 1984-June 1985 (Box 97, Folder 1-27)
      - PDC (General -Chron) Materials, July 1985-February 1986 (Box 98, Folder 1-25)
      - CISAC (Stanford), March 1986-1987 (Box 99, Folder 1-21)
      - PDC (General -Chron) Materials, January 1987-February 1991 (Box 100, Folder 1-39)
      - PDC (General -Chron) Materials, August 1989-February 1991 (Box 101, Folder 1-41)
      - PDC (General -Chron) Materials, March 1991-January 1992 (Box 102, Folder 1-37)
      - Ethnocentric Violence drafts & other DAH writing, 1992-January 1993 (Box 103, Folder 1-27)
      - PDC meetings, Vance-Hamburg commission, and youth violence, March 1993-December 1993 (Box 104, Folder 1-45)
      - Carnegie Commission on Prevention of Deadly Conflict (CCPDC) creation and members, 1994-1996 (Box 105, Folder 1-25)
      - CCPDC grants & meetings, 1994-October 1994 (Box 106, Folder 1-28)
      - CCPDC activities, Harvard democracy discussion, November 1994-April 1995 (Box 107, Folder 1-32)
      - CCPDC meetinggs & conferences, April 1995-August 1995 (Box 108, Folder 1-18)
      - CCPDC meetinggs & conferences; PCAST, September 1995-1996 (Box 109, Folder 1-40)
      - CCPDC final report material, South Africa issues, January 1996-June 1996 (Box 110, Folder 1-27)
      - CCPDC final report, July 1996-December 1996 (Box 111, Folder 1-33)
      - PDC Chron (India/ Pakistan & China), 1996-1997 (Box 112, Folder 1-19)
      - Subject files, 1997- (Box 112, Folder 20-52)
      - CCPDC final report, UNHCR and Kofi Annan, 1997-April 1997 (Box 113, Folder 1-38)
      - CCPDC final report, UNHCR and Kofi Annan, April 1997-June 1997 (Box 114, Folder 1-44)
      - CCPDC final report and materials, July 1997- (Box 115, Folder 1-39)
      - CCPDC final report and materials, August 1997-September 1997 (Box 116, Folder 1-46)
        Robert Rubin/Hilary Clinton Correspondence
      - CCPDC final report and materials, October 1997-December 1997 (Box 117, Folder 1-40)
        Hilary Clinton Correspondence
      - CCPDC final report and launch materials, December 1997- (Box 118, Folder 1-30)
      - CCPDC final report and launch materials, 1997-1998 (Box 119, Folder 1-21)
      - CCPDC final report presentations, Kofi Annan and United Nations meetings, January 1998-February 1998 (Box 120, Folder 1-35)
      - CCPDC and United Nations, March 1998-April 1998 (Box 121, Folder 1-40)
      - Subject files, May 1998-September 1998 (Box 122, Folder 1-34)
      - Preventive Diplomacy & Preventive Defence (PD2) Conference with Stanford, August 1998-January 1999 (Box 123, Folder 1-25 [and 44-48])
      - United Nations meetings, September 1998-November 1998 (Box 123, Folder 26-51)
      - Subject files, essays and publications, November 1998-March 1999 (Box 124, Folder 1-47)
      - Conference reports; ccpdc publications & closing/farewell letters, April 1999-2000 (Box 125, Folder 1-54)
        Al Gore & Bill Clinton; UN Security Council retreat
      - Subject files, January 2000-February 2001 (Box 126, Folder 1-38)
      - Margaret & Eric Hamburg materials; United Nations projects, March 2001-2003 (Box 127, Folder 1-47)
      - undated materials (Box 128, Folder 1-47)
      - Meeting Materials and Briefing Books, 1994-1995 (Box 129, Folder 1-12)
      - Meeting Materials and Briefing Books, 1996-1997 (Box 130, Folder 1-8)
      - Meeting Materials and Briefing Books, comments, 1996-1997 (Box 131, Folder 1-8)
    - Sub-subseries I.7.B: PDC Background
      Series consists of clippings with manuscript notes by Hamburg, journal articles, notes, and typescripts of work by others, such as papers by Joseph Nye, Sidney Drell and other prominent scientists. This group of documents also includes general materials on conflict prevention, war and ethnic conflict, including materials on specific conflicts/countries. It includes materials on conflict resolution and terrorism from Dr. Hamburg’s pre-Carnegie projects.
      - Background Materials, 1972-1983 (Box 132, Folder 1-34)
      - Background Materials, Eastern Bloc, 1983-1988 (Box 133, Folder 1-58)
      - Background Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 134, Folder 1-40)
      - Background Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 135, Folder 1-72)
      - Background, AST book summary memos, 1993-1994 (Box 136, Folder 1-18)
      - Background Materials, 1993- (Box 137, Folder 1-45)
      - Background Materials, 1994-October 1996 (Box 138, Folder 1-57)
      - Background Materials, November 1996-1997 (Box 139, Folder 1-20)
      - Background India, Pakistan & China materials, 1997-2000 (Box 139, Folder 21-51)
      - Background Materials, 1997-November 1997 (Box 140, Folder 1-56)
      - Preventive Diplomacy & Preventive Defence (PD2) Conference background materials, December 1997-April 1998 (Box 141, Folder 1-51)
      - Background Materials including Culture of Peace Program in Jordan, May 1998-1999 (Box 142, Folder 1-71)
      - Background Materials, 2000-July 2001 (Box 143, Folder 1-71)
      - Background Materials, International Crisis Group, etc., August 2001-2003 (Box 144, Folder 1-57)
      - Background Materials, undated materials- (Box 144, Folder 58-69)
      - Background Materials, undated materials- (Box 145, Folder 1-45)
    - Sub-subseries I.7.C: PDC Stages
      This group of files was organized into subjects ("stages" of dealing with the problem of conflict resolution) by Hamburg; filed in original order including background. The series contains some undated folders throughout, and some materials may have later been removed and included the PDC general, chronological series.
      - PDC stages: "The Predicament" ("new wine in old bottles," proliferation, escalation, etc.), 1984-1993 (Box 146, Folder 1-11)
      - PDC stages: "How did we get into it? Evolutionary perspective, historical developments, recent history", 1992-1993 (Box 146, Folder 12-15)
      - PDC Stages: "How can we get out of it? Principles and techniques of conflict resolution (CR)", 1989-1993 (Box 146, Folder 16-37)
      - PDC Stages: "How can we get out of it? Principles and techniques of conflict resolution (CR)", 1987-1993 (Box 147, Folder 1-15)
      - PDC Stages: "Cure II --Dissemination through education, CBOs, media, etc…", 1986-1993 (Box 147, Folder 16-21)
      - PDC Stages: "Cure III--Cold War: Lessons learned for CR", 1983-1993 (Box 147, Folder 22-37)
      - PDC Stages: "Cure III--Cold War: Lessons learned for CR", 1983-1993 (Box 148, Folder 1-31)
      - PDC Stages: Cure V (Ethnocentric Violence), 1993- (Box 148, Folder 32)
      - PDC Stages: "Cure VI--SDI2 (including LDC and/or LDC in INC)", 1990-1993 (Box 148, Folder 33-42)
    - Sub-subseries I.7.D: PDC Alphabetical Files
      Alphabetical subject files in original order by Hamburg, including background files. Some subjects overlap with non-PDC series, such as Developing Human Resources in Developing Countries. The voluminous “Democracy” file includes "Ray Marshall Papers", "Renewing the Agenda for Democracy" with Hilary Clinton, and non-CCNY materials.
      - Africa, 1995-1997 (Box 149, Folder 1-7)
        15
      - Aggression, 1965-1988 (Box 149, Folder 8-11)
      - Bosnia, 1993-1997 (Box 149, Folder 12-21)
      - Business, 1996-1997 (Box 149, Folder 22-35)
      - Causes of War, 1983-1998 (Box 150, Folder 1-8)
      - China, 1996-1996 (Box 150, Folder 9-11)
      - Conflict Resolution and Psychology, 1995-1995 (Box 150, Folder 12-13)
      - Constituency for Prevention, 1995-1997 (Box 150, Folder 14-22)
      - Democracy, 1994-1997 (Box 150, Folder 23-60)
      - Democracy, 1984-1997 (Box 151, Folder 1-34)
      - Democracy, 1990-1997 (Box 152, Folder 1-50)
      - Democracy, 1988-1997 (Box 153, Folder 1-36)
      - Development, 1994-1996 (Box 153, Folder 37-42)
      - Education for Conflict Resolution, 1988-1997 (Box 154, Folder 1-32)
      - Evolution, 1997-1997 (Box 155, Folder 1)
      - Genocide, 1995-1997 (Box 155, Folder 2-5)
      - Graham Allison (GTA) Related, 1994-1997 (Box 155, Folder 6-29)
      - Gorbachev State of the World, 1993-1996 (Box 155, Folder 30-35)
      - India/Pakistan, 1995-1996 (Box 155, Folder 36-40)
      - International Law, 1996-1997 (Box 156, Folder 1-5)
      - Leadership, 1987-1997 (Box 156, Folder 6-27)
      - Media, 1994-1997 (Box 156, Folder 28-42)
      - Mideast, 1988-1990 (Box 157, Folder 1-10)
      - Military, 1996-1996 (Box 157, Folder 11-14)
      - Nationalism/ Ethnicity, 1995-1995 (Box 157, Folder 15-17)
      - Preventive Diplomacy, 1993-1996 (Box 157, Folder 18-39)
      - Proliferation [Prevention of Proliferation (PoP)], 1992-1997 (Box 157, Folder 40-49)
      - Proliferation [Prevention of Proliferation (PoP)], 1984-1997 (Box 158, Folder 1-38)
      - Religion, 1983-1996 (Box 158, Folder 39)
      - Russia, 1993-1995 (Box 158, Folder 40-52)
      - Russia/FSU [Former Soviet Union], 1990-1996 (Box 159, Folder 1-45)
      - Russia/FSU, 1992-1995 (Box 160, Folder 1-51)
      - Russia/FSU, 1990-1996 (Box 161, Folder 1-40)
      - Sanctions/Incentives, 1993-1996 (Box 161, Folder 41-43)
      - Science and Technology, including Velikhov-Hamburg Project, 1996-1997 (Box 162, Folder 1-4)
      - Terrorism, 1996-1997 (Box 162, Folder 5-14)
      - UNHCR, 1996-1997 (Box 162, Folder 15-19)
      - United Nations, 1993-1997 (Box 162, Folder 20-48)
      - United Nations - conflict resolution, 1992-1997 (Box 163, Folder 1-39)
      - World Transformed/ Globalization, 1989-1997 (Box 163, Folder 40-46)
  - Subseries I.8: Eastern Block
    Materials relating to conflicts in/with Eastern Bloc Countries and assistance to them from various CCNY programs, including Avoiding Nuclear War, Cooperative Security, and partially Preventing Deadly Conflict (mostly covered in Series I.7). The Eastern Bloc subseries also documents Hamburg’s activities, writings and communications relating to the former Soviet Union and its Eastern European allies, the Carnegie Corporation’s sponsorship of work with these countries performed by other institutions, such as Harvard, Stanford, United Nations Association of the United States of America, Aspen Strategy Group, AAAS, IREX, IOM, and others. Materials on Committee on International Security and Arms Control (CISAC) are described in separate Series I.10.
    - Sub-subseries I.8.A: General
      Administrative and general subject files pertaining to the Soviet Union and its satellites in the context of Avoiding Nuclear War, East-West Security Studies and Preventing Deadly Conflict programs, projects in science, technology and educations, and building democratic mechanisms after the fall of the Soviet Union. The subseries contains materials about meeting, conferences, Carnegie-supported IREX projects in Russia, and Dr. Hamburg’s visits to Moscow, and other Soviet and Eastern European locations. It also covers Nunn-Lugar Task Force to work with Belarus, Kazakhstan, Ukraine and Russia on dismantling their nuclear weapons. The subseries documents the period of rapid changes and eventual dissolution of the Soviet system, and includes eyewitness accounts and materials on and by Soviet leaders, including Mikhail Gorbachev (see also Correspondence series). The files are arranged in loose chronological order.
      - CCNY International Conflict & Cooperation Working Group, writings on Soviet Union, 1982-June 1983 (Box 164, Folder 1-23)
      - Various project files, including IREX and ANW, August 1983-March 1988 (Box 165, Folder 1-20)
      - Various project files, including IREX and ANW, April 1984-1985 (Box 166, Folder 1-24)
      - Various project files, Hamburg Moscow trip, 1985-February 1985 (Box 167, Folder 1-17)
      - Various project files, including IREX and CISAC, March 1985-November 1985 (Box 168, Folder 1-26)
      - Eastern Bloc materials, December 1985-February 1986 (Box 169, Folder 1-29)
      - East-West Security Studies, Conferences, March 1986-October 1986 (Box 170, Folder 1-22)
      - East-West Security Studies, Conferences, November 1986-January 1987 (Box 171, Folder 1-22)
      - East-West Security Studies, Conferences, Moscow meetings, January 1987-August 1987 (Box 172, Folder 1-30)
      - Various project files, August 1987-1988 (Box 173, Folder 1-22)
      - CCNY Moscow Trip on CISAC, January 1988-March 1988 (Box 174, Folder 1-35)
      - Conferences and memoranda, April 1988-August 1988 (Box 175, Folder 1-24)
      - Various project files, September 1988-1989 (Box 176, Folder 1-24)
      - Various project files, 1989-July 1989 (Box 177, Folder 1-41)
      - Meetings in Russia and Eastern Europe, September 1989-December 1989 (Box 178, Folder 1-32)
      - Arms Control Conference and Carnegie grants, 1990-May 1990 (Box 179, Folder 1-31)
      - Aid to Soviet Union, Cooperative Security program, June 1990-February 1991 (Box 180, Folder 1-36)
      - Harvard Files and Moscow Trip Reports, March 1991-October 1991 (Box 181, Folder 1-42)
      - Dissolution of Soviet Union, October 1991-February 1992 (Box 182, Folder 1-45)
      - Harvard Memoranda and subject files, March 1992-September 1992 (Box 183, Folder 1-34)
      - Project on Ethnic Relations, Moscow Trip and Yugoslavia, September 1992-August 1993 (Box 184, Folder 1-42)
      - Various project files, September 1993-November 1996 (Box 185, Folder 1-41)
      - Nunn Task Force, conferences, December 1996-February 1998 (Box 186, Folder 1-51)
      - Nunn-Lugar Task Force, US-Russia Dialogue, March 1998-1999 (Box 187, Folder 1-31)
      - Nunn-Lugar Task Force, US-Russia Dialogue, 2000-2002 (Box 188, Folder 1-26)
      - Gorbachev Leadership draft, notes and writings, undated- (Box 188, Folder 27-44)
    - Sub-subseries I.8.B: Background
      The subseries contains news clippings, printed matter, conference materials, notes, and typescripts of third-party papers and memoranda, includes Kennan Institute and Harriman Institute materials, on the issues of Eastern Bloc and its leadership, possible impact of Nuclear War; U.S.-Soviet perceptions of each other, security concerns, and so on.
      - U.S.-Soviet perceptions of each other; Medical impact of Nuclear War, 1965-1983 (Box 189, Folder 1-25)
      - Eastern Bloc Background Materials, 1983-1985 (Box 190, Folder 1-44)